Register of the Howard Palfrey Jones papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1934-1973 (Box 1-20)
  - Tierney, Thomas M., 1966
  - Time, Inc., 1966-1968
  - Tjahjono, Henty, 1966
  - Tjanorawibawa, Renatus, 1969
  - Tjokroadisumarto, Widjonarko, 1966
  - Tojib, 1967-1968
  - Tokuyama, Jiro, 1967
  - Tolman, Norman H., 1969
  - Tong, Hollington, 1965-1966
  - Toussaint, Donald R., 1968
  - Towl, Andrew R., 1972
  - Trager, Frank N., 1968
  - Travelodge Corporation, 1968
  - Trawan, 1968
  - Traythan, Dr., 1967
  - Trent, Mary Vance, 1959-1971
  - Troster, Marguerite, 1970
  - Trott, Lamarr B., 1968
  - Trumbull, Robert, 1965-1967
  - Tsang, Chiu-sam, 1969
  - Tse, K. K., 1962-1968
  - Tsouvalis, Mary, 1968
  - Tsukiyama, Martha, 1968
  - Tubby, Roger, 1961
  - Tullis, Garner H., 1969
  - Tuthill, John W., 1962
  - Tweedy, Mr. and Mrs. Gordon B., 1966-1967
  - Tweedy, Mary Johnson, 1966-1971
  - Twigg-Smith, Thurston, 1965-1966
  - Tyler, Josephine, 1966
  - Tyler, William R., 1962
  - Tyrrell, W. B., 1968
  - Ulinski, John A., Jr., 1966 (Box 19)
  - Underhill, Francis, T., Jr., 1971
  - Unger, Leonard, 1969-1970
  - United Airlines, 1969
  - U.S. Department of State, 1957-1971
  - U.S. Peace Corps, 1962-1966
  - University Affiliates, University of California, Los Angeles, 1965
  - University of Denver, Denver, Colorado, 1968
  - University of Oregon, 1967
  - Van Den Berghe, L. A., 1966-1967
  - Vandivier, Philip F., 1962-1964
  - Van Dusen, A. C., 1965
  - Van Orsdel, Ralph A., Jr., 1968
  - Van Stirnum, John, 1969
  - Van Swearingen, J. A., 1965-1966
  - Van Vorst, William D., 1966-1971
  - Vereniging Van Nederlandse Gemeenten, 1948
  - Vernon Church Flowers, 1968
  - Veteran's Administration, 1963
  - Viddicombe, Edward, 1960
  - Vilmur, Robert, 1965
  - Viner, George, 1968
  - Vittrup, R. L., 1964
  - Von Benschoten, Birney, 1964
  - Votaw, Maurice E., 1965
  - Wackermann, Robert L., 1967
  - Waddell, H. Newton, 1966
  - Wager, Paul, 1966
  - Wajima, Eiji, 1968
  - Walker, D. Merle, 1965-1967
  - Walker, Mrs. H. Alexander, 1963-1968
  - Walker, Henry A., Jr., 1968
  - Walkin, 1965-1970
  - Wall, A. E. P., 1965
  - Wallerstein, Morton L., 1968-1971
  - Wanacek, Earl M., 1972
  - Wang, Gen. S. M., 1965-1966
  - Warner, H. H., 1964
  - Warwick, J. R., 1971
  - Watrous, Jerome A., 1962-1967
  - Watt, James, 1971
  - Weaver, Mrs. Samuel P., 1965
  - Weidner, Edward W., 1966
  - Weiss, Carl, 1962
  - Weitz, Rudolph W., 1962-1971
  - Weiz, G., 1964
  - Welch, Wilford H., 1971
  - Wellesley College, Wellesley, Mass., 1966
  - Wells, Herman B., 1963-1965
  - Wells, Neilson P., 1970
  - Welsh, D. J., 1962
  - West, Susan W., 1970
  - Western Concrete Reinforcing Steel Institute, 1969
  - Western U.S. - Indonesia Chamber of Commerce, 1970
  - Westminster College, New Wilmington, Pa., 1958
  - Westphal, Albert C. F., 1966-1968
  - Wheeler, Crawford, 1962-1965
  - Wheeler, Rae, 1967
  - Whinery, Marion, 1961
  - Whipple, Dorothy, 1966-1967
  - Whitehill, Clayton, 1961-1962
  - Whitted, S. F., 1966
  - Whittington, Floyd L., 1963-1969
  - Wick, Charles Z., 1965
  - Widjojo, Nitisastro, 1972
  - Wiggins, J. R., 1960-1971
  - Wilcox, Francis O., 1962-1964
  - Wilder, Mrs. Kinau, 1967
  - Willenbrock, Mildred, 1962-1970
  - Williams, Diane D., 1969-1970
  - Williams, Francis, 1960
  - Williams, J. Emlyn, 1970
  - Williams, Ruth M., 1965-1967
  - Willner, Roth Ann, 1967
  - Willoughby, Alfred, 1957-1971
  - Willoughby, Betty C., 1962
  - Wilsey, H. Lawrence, 1965-1967
  - Wilson, Howard E., 1965
  - Wilson, Logan, 1968
  - Wilson, Willard, 1965
  - Winkler, Bruno O., 1964-1966
  - Winn, Conchita, 1964-1967
  - Winn, Ed, Jr., 1964
  - Winn, Edward B., 1960-1967
  - Wirosuhardjo, Kartomo, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Witeck, John M., 1968
  - Witeck, Mrs. John M., 1968
  - Wohl, Paul, 1970
  - Wolfe, Bertram D., 1970
  - Woo, Manuel, 1967-1968
  - Woodbury, Susan, 1966
  - Woodman, Everett M., 1972
  - Woods, Ray, 1966
  - Woodward, Helen, 1971
  - Woodward, Vernon E., 1965-1971
  - World Affairs Council, 1968
  - Wright, James A., 1968-1971
  - Wright, Timothy W., 1967
  - Wukasch, Don C., 1964
  - Wyatt, Wilson W., 1963-1972
  - Wyman, Oliver B., 1955
  - Yamada, Tadayoshi, 1962-1971
  - Yamamoto, George, 1968
  - Yamato, Kei C., 1966-1970
  - Yamin, R. A. Siti Sundari, 1963
  - Yee, S. K., 1967-1970
  - Yen Chia-kan, 1964-1971
  - Yost, Charles W., 1972
  - Young, Alice, 1965
  - Young, Clarence W., 1971
  - Young, John P., 1966
  - Young, Kenneth, 1967-1968
  - Yuchengco, Mrs. Paz, 1963
  - Yuen Chen-yu, 1968
  - Zain, Zairin, 1964
  - Zdunek, E. W., 1962
  - Zilmer, Bertram G., 1969
  - Zítek, Jan, 1958
- Speeches and Writings, 1950-1971 (Box 21-49)
  Drafts, manuscripts, and printed copies of speeches and articles by Howard P. Jones, arranged alphabetically by title or subject. The drafts for Jones' book Indonesia: The Possible Dream are arranged by arbitrarily assigned letters to differentiate between them and are not necessarily in the order in which they were written.
  - "America and Indonesia," speech to the American Association in Djakarta, 1958 April 8; 3 copies in English, 1 copy in Indonesian (2 printed, 1 typewritten, 1 carbon). (Box 21)
  - "America Faces Asia," speech to the Graduate School of Banking, University of Wisconsin, 1965 August 24; 6 copies (2 printed, 2 typewritten, 2 carbons).
  - "American Aid in Asia,", undated; 4 copies.
  - "American Image in Indonesia," Far East Chiefs of Mission Conference, Baguio, 1962; 1 carbon copy.
  - "American-Indonesian Relations," speech at the Chiefs of Mission Conference, Baguio, the Philippines; slightly altered version of this speech to the Council on Foreign Relations, New York, New York, 1965; 4 copies (2 carbons of each version).
  - "America's Responsibilities and Opportunities in Asia," speech at the University of Denver, University of Utah, and Boise Valley World Affairs Association, Boise, Idaho, 1957 January; 2 carbon copies.
  - "Approach to a New Nation,", undated; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon).
  - "Asia - A Study in Contrasts," speech to the Western Concrete Steel Institute, Monterey, California, speech appears in its Proceedings of the Annual Spring Conference, p. 9, 1969 May 14
  - "Asia Through Indonesian Eyes," speech at the Asia-Pacific Seminar, East-West Center, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1966 January 21; 2 photocopies.
  - "Berlin Family," typed draft, undated
  - "Broadest Concept of Conscience and National Service," speech to the Special Interest Meeting of Biennial Meeting, 1971 August 27; 8 copies (2 typewritten, 5 photocopies, 1 draft).
  - "Building Mutual Understanding," speech to the Djakarta Rotary Club, 1968 November 25; 2 printed copies.
  - "Can Germany Be Democratized?," typed draft, undated
  - "Civil Service Program for Germany," typed draft, undated
  - "Contempt of Court," unpublished manuscript, undated
    - Chapters 1 through 19
    - Chapter 20 through summary (Box 22)
  - "Contempt of Court" case studies, arranged alphabetically by state (47 states included), typed carbons, undated
  - "Countering the Soviet Threat in the Far East," article in the Department of State Bulletin, printed copy, 1956 July 16
  - "Crisis in Asia," speech at the Annual District 500 Conference of Rotary International, 1966 April 22; 3 carbon copies.
  - "Decade of Change in Southeast Asia," speech to the American Society of Newspaper Editors, Washington, D.C., 1960 April 23; 7 printed copies.
  - Diary notes, 1964
    October 13, 1964 (3 copies), October 15, 1964 (1 copy), January, 1964 (1 copy).
  - "Do We Really Want Peace?,", undated; 1 mimeographed copy.
  - "The East-West Center - Its Purposes, Its Prospects, Its Potential,", undated; 2 drafts.
  - "Economic Problems in Asia," reprint of an article from the Department of State Bulletin, 1956
  - "Education for Tomorrow in Asia and the Pacific,", 1966 September 14; 1 carbon.
  - "Encounter With the Soviet Secret Police,", undated; 5 copies (1 typewritten, 4 carbons).
  - "Engineering and the Building of Nations," speech to the Planning Meeting for an International Conference on the Role of the Engineer in Development of Emerging Nations, 1967 February 13; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon).
  - "Fraulein's Road," article in The American Legion Magazine, 1961 July; 6 copies (2 printed copies, 4 carbons).
  - "How the Christian Science Sentinel and the Herald of Christian Science Help the Individual Christian Scientist in the Healing of the Nations,", undated; 3 copies (2 typewritten, 1 photocopy).
  - "Impressions of Japan,", 1971 October; 1 typewritten copy. (Box 23)
  - "Importance of Asia," article in Vital Speeches of the Day, printed copy, 1962 November
  - "Importance of Supporting Cultural Activities in the Community," speech to the Honolulu Symphony Society, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1967 September 28; 2 copies (typewritten, 1 carbon).
  - "Indonesia: A New World Power Emerges," speech at the World Affairs Council, San Francisco, California, 1962 October 30; 6 copies (2 typewritten, 3 carbons, 1 photocopy).
  - "Indonesia Alters Its Course," speech to Members of the War College, Washington, D.C., 1966 March 1; 1 carbon copy.
  - "Indonesia: Anchorman of Southeast Asia," speech to the Commonwealth Club of California, 1968 September 6; 2 copies (1 photocopy, 1 carbon).
  - "Indonesia - Land of Promise,", 1956 October; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon).
  - "Indonesia 1969," speech to the American Men's Association, undated; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 photocopy).
  - Indonesia: The Possible Dream, New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Inc., 1971
    - Draft A, Part I, Foreward, Chapters 1-6
    - Draft A, Part II, Chapters 1-3
    - Draft A, Part II, Chapters 4-14 (Box 24)
    - Draft A, Part III, Chapters 1-9 (Box 25)
    - Draft A, Part III, Chapters 10-14; Part IV, Chapter 4 (Box 26)
    - Draft B (Box 27)
    - Draft C, 20 chapters. (Box 28)
    - Draft C, 17 chapters. (Box 29)
    - Draft D (Box 30)
    - Draft E (Box 31)
    - Draft F (Box 32)
    - Draft G (Box 33)
    - Draft H, Prologue - Chapter 16 (Box 34)
    - Draft H, Epilogue - Chapter 17 (Box 35)
    - Draft I (Box 36)
    - Draft J, Foreward - Part III, Chapter 2
    - Draft J, Part III, Chapter 3; Appendix B (Box 37)
    - Acknowledgments (Box 38)
    - Biographies of principal characters
    - Glossary
    - Title page
    - Selected bibliography
    - Extra chapters
    - Permissions
    - Index
    - Rough draft, notes (Box 39-43)
    - Scrapbook of reviews, correspondence, clippings (Box 44)
  - "Inside East Germany,", undated; 6 copies (2 typewritten, 1 photocopy, 3 carbons). (Box 45)
  - "Insular Southeast Asia,", 1966 March 1; 2 copies (1 carbon, 1 photocopy)
  - Introductions for speakers
    - Sidney Cottle, undated
    - John K. Emmerson, 1969 June 19
    - Paul Hanna, undated
    - President Sukarno, 1963 October 9
  - "Is Christian Science Relevant to the Diplomatic Service?,", 1971(?); 1 photocopy.
  - "Is the Tide Turning in Asia?," speech to the American Society of Newspaper Editors, Washington, D.C., 1960 April 23; 8 copies (3 typewritten, 1 carbon, 2 Department of State reprints, 1 printed copy from the Air Intelligence Training Bulletin, September 1960, 1 USIS Special Release reprint).
  - "Make the 'E' in Travel Stand for Education," speech to the Pacific Area Travel Association, Taipei, Taiwan, news release copy from the East-West Center, 1968 February 13
  - Miscellaneous notes, drafts, outlines
  - Miscellaneous speech notes, clippings, outlines, parts of speeches
  - "Nationalism and Beyond," speech to the Manila Rotary Club, Manila, the Philippines, USIS reprint, 1963 August 8
  - "Nederlandse Omroep Stichting," radio panel discussion, 1970 May 24
  - "Need for Innovation," speech at the First Church of Christ, Scientist, Concord, Massachusetts, 1971 May 2; 2 typewritten copies.
  - "A New Dimension in Foreign Affairs," speech at Colby Junior College, New London, New Hampshire and Juniata College, Huntingdon, Pennsylvania, 1970; 8 copies (1 typewritten, 5 photocopies, 1 printed), part of draft, extra pages, excerpts.
  - "The New Dimension in Foreign Affairs," Central Union Church, 1967 October 18; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon).
  - "The New Dimension in International Affairs," speech to 1967 Rotary International Convention, Nice, France; slightly altered version of this speech to the Commonwealth Club of California, San Francisco, California, 1967, 1968; 9 copies (5 printed copies, 2 typewritten, 1 photocopy, 1 carbon) of the Rotary International version; 2 carbon copies of the Commonwealth Club version.
  - "New Dimensions in International Understanding," speech to the Friends and Alumni of the University of Hawaii, Hilo Campus, 1967 November 16; 1 carbon copy.
  - "The New Germany,", undated; 1 carbon copy. (Box 46)
  - "A New Indonesia Emerges,", undated; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon).
  - "The New Nation: Some Considerations of Psychology and Approach,", undated; 4 copies (1 typewritten, 3 carbons), 1 draft.
  - "1934. Black Clouds on the Horizon,", undated; 4 copies (1 typewritten, 2 carbons, 1 mixed).
  - "Olga, a Russian Woman," (possible title), unpublished manuscript, undated
  - "On the Governance of the University," speech, typed draft, 1965 November 4
  - "Operation Scarlet Pimpernel,", undated; 6 copies (1 typewritten, 5 carbons).
  - Oral history interview for the John F. Kennedy Library
    - Palo Alto, California, 1969 June 23; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 photocopy).
    - Boston, Massachusetts, 1970 March 20; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 photocopy).
    - Boston, Massachusetts, 1970 April 9; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 photocopy).
  - "The Pacific Era - Portents for Peace or War," speech at the 51st Annual Meeting, National Association of County Agricultural Agents, East-West Center, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1966 November 2; 3 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon, 1 photocopy).
  - "Prospects for American Business in Southeast Asia," Hawaiian Sugar Planter's Association Meeting, 1967 December 5; 1 photocopy, 1 draft.
  - "The Role of the East-West Center in the Development of the Pacific Basin," speech to the American Society for Engineering Education, 1966 December 28; 1 typewritten copy.
  - "Seeing the Spice Islands with Sukarno,", undated; 5 copies (2 typewritten, 3 carbons). (Box 47)
  - "Situation in Indonesia as of October 7, 1965,", 1965 October 7; 1 photocopy.
  - "The Sparks Fly Upward,", undated; 1 photocopy, note
  - Speech at Akademi Ilmu Pelajaran Open House, 1964 June 3; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon).
  - Speech at Fairleigh-Dickinson University, Rutherford, New Jersey, 1962 October 6; 1 carbon copy.
  - Speech at the American Men's Association Dinner, 1959 December 23; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech at the American Men's Association Luncheon for President Sukarno, 1964 December 22; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech at the Ceremony Aboard the S.S. "Steel Executive" Marking the Arrival of Equipment for the Urea Fertilizer Plant, Palembang, Indonesia, 1961 November 15; 1 carbon copy. (Proposed)
  - Speech at the Ceremony Dedicating the New Building at the Public Service Center, Gadjah Mada University, Jogjakarta, Indonesia, 1961 September 19; 4 copies (1 carbon, 3 USIS Special Release reprints), 1 draft, notes.
  - Speech at the Cornerstone Laying Ceremony of the Hall to House the U.S.-Provided Atomic Reactor in Bandung, Indonesia, 1961 April 9; 1 USIS Special Release reprint.
  - Speech at the Dedication Ceremony of the Sriwidjaja Fertilizer Plant, 1964 July 4; 2 USIS Special Release reprints, 1 carbon copy (proposed).
  - Speech at the Dedication of the Djakarta By-Pass Highway, undated; 2 carbon copies.
  - Speech at the Dedication of the Jefferson Library, Jogjakarta, Indonesia, 1959 December 28; 3 copies (2 typewritten, 1 carbon), 1 rough draft.
  - Speech at the Dedication of the Little Mosquito Island, V. O. R., 1964 February 26; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech at the Dedication of the New Chancery, Djakarta, Indonesia, 1958 September 24; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech at the Governor's Prayer Breakfast, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1966 February 18; 3 copies (2 typewritten, 1 carbon), 2 newspapers clippings of speech.
  - Speech at the Labor Day Reception Given at the American Embassy, Djakarta, Indonesia, 1960 September 5; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 USIS Special Release reprint).
  - Speech at the Opening of the U.S. Space and Economic Development Exhibit at Bandung, Indonesia, 1962 December 27; 4 copies (1 typewritten, 3 USIS reprints).
  - Speech at the Presentation of a T-34 Airplane, 1961 October 27; 1 typewritten copy, 2 drafts.
  - Speech at the Recognition Ceremony, Kennedy Theatre, University of Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii, news release copy from the East-West Center, 1968 May 31
  - Speech at the Signing of the Food-For-Peace Program, 1961 October 26; 3 copies (1 carbon, 1 photocopy, 1 mimeograph).
  - Speech at the Signing of the Food-For-Peace Program, 1962 February 19; 1 carbon copy (proposed), notes.
  - Speech at the Signing of the Food Program Agreement, 1960 December 23; 1 carbon copy (proposed), notes.
  - Speech at the Signing of the Third Surplus Agricultural Commodities Agreement, 1960 November 5; 1 carbon copy (proposed), notes.
  - Speech Before the German World Economic Society, 1950 October 2; 1 carbon copy.
  - Speech for Luncheon (proposed), undated; 1 carbon copy.
  - Speech on Independence Day, 1961 July 4; 1 carbon copy.
  - Speech on Independence Day, 1962 July 4; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech on Independence Day, 1963 July 4; 1 USIS Special Release reprint, 1 draft.
  - Speech on Independence Day, 1964 July 4; 1 USIS Special Release reprint.
  - Speech on the Occasion of Ceremonies for the New USOM Building, 1960 December 5; 1 typewritten copy (proposed), notes.
  - Speech on the Occasion of Presenting Three Indonesian Pieces from the "Asian Artists in Crystal" Exhibit to President Sukarno at Tjipanas, Indonesia, 1959 August 1; 1 carbon copy. (proposed).
  - Speech on the Occasion of the Signing of the First Development Loan Fund Agreements with Indonesia, 1959 June 26; 1 typewritten copy (proposed).
  - Speech on the Occasion of the Starting of the M.T.T. Supported Training at Bogor, Indonesia, 1963 September 2; 1 typewritten copy with handwritten notes.
  - Speech on the Opening of the International Shop, notes, 1964 November 30
  - Speech on the Turning Over of Vehicles to the Indonesian Red Cross from the American Red Cross, 1962 June 30; 1 carbon copy (proposed).
  - Speech on U.S. Foreign Policy, 1959 June 4; 1 typewritten copy, 1 mimeographed synopsis.
  - Speech to Sukarno, notes, 1964 July 16
  - Speech to the American Businessmen's Club, draft, 1964 February 19 (Box 48)
  - Speech to the American Indonesian Chamber of Commerce, New York, New York, 1962 October 17; 3 copies (2 typewritten, 1 photocopy).
  - Speech to the American Men's Association, Djakarta, Indonesia, 1969 February 4; 1 typewritten copy. 1 draft.
  - Speech to the American Men's Association, Djakarta, Indonesia, undated; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech to the Business Advisory Council, Hot Springs, Virginia, 1960 May 13; 10 copies (9 mimeographed, 1 carbon), 1 draft.
  - Speech to the Delegates to the Mexico-United States Inter-parliamentary Conference, 1968 April 12; 5 copies (1 typewritten, 4 News Release from the East-West Center reprints).
  - Speech to the Djakarta Rotary Club, 1958 November 25; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech to the First Church of Christ, Scientist, Menlo Park, California, 1969 August; 1 draft.
  - Speech to the Foreign Affairs Committee of the Parliament of the Republic of Indonesia, 1959 February 5; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon).
  - Speech to the Foundation, Charlestown, New Hampshire, 1971 May 16; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 photocopy), 1 outline.
  - Speech to the Fourth Biennial Japan-American Pacific Area Conference of Mayors and Chamber of Commerce Presidents, 1957 November 5; 2 Department of State press release reprints.
  - Speech to the Graduating Class, Principia Upper School, St. Louis, Missouri, 1968 June 1; 12 copies of the speech in booklet entitled "Progress at Principia," 1 Commencement program.
  - Speech to the Honolulu Federal Executive Association, Tenth Annual Awards Luncheon, 1966 April 20; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech to the Journalism Faculty and Students of Padjadjaran University, 1963 May 13; 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon).
  - Speech to the National Foreign Trade Council, New York, New York, 1956 April 4; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech to the Pacific Conference on Urban Growth, news release from the East-West Center reprints, 1967 May 2
  - Speech to the Royal Institute of International Affairs, London, England, 1969 February; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech to University Presidents, Washington, D.C., 1956 April 17; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Statement for The Honolulu Advertiser, 1966 April 26; 2 carbon copies, 1 newspaper clipping. (Box 49)
  - Statement on Cancellation of Entertainment of the Crew of the U.S. Cruiser St. Paul, 1959 November 2; 2 USIS Special Release reprints.
  - Statement on President Eisenhower, 1969 March 28; 1 carbon copy.
  - Statement on the Occasion of Indonesian Hero's Day, 1960; 4 copies (1 typewritten, 3 carbons).
  - Statement Upon Arrival in Djakarta, 1960 July 29; 9 copies (1 typewritten, 8 carbons).
  - "Ten Years of Indonesian-American Economic Cooperation," original and updated versions, 1961, 1962; 1 mimeographed copy.
  - "The Three Faces of Asia," speech at Ricks College, Rexburg, Idaho, 1968 October 3; 1 typewritten copy with handwritten notes.
  - "Tomorrow's Indonesia,", undated; 7 copies (1 typewritten, 6 photocopies).
  - "Toward Understanding," speech to the American Men's Association, Djakarta, Indonesia, 1965 February 2; 8 copies (1 typewritten, 4 carbons, 3 USIS Special Release reprints), 2 drafts.
  - "Toward Understanding New Nations,", undated; 2 copies (1 mimeographed, carbon).
  - "Turnaround in Indonesia," Reader's Digest, 1970 March; 1 typewritten copy.
  - "Under Pressure? There's a Way Out," The Truth That Heals, a Christian Science Radio Series, 1971 November 7; 1 radio program transcript.
  - "U.S. Economic Policy and Programs in the Far East," speech to the Far East-America Council of Commerce and Industry, New York, New York, 1956 October 4; 1 typewritten copy, 1 reprint from the Department of State Bulletin, October 22, 1956.
  - "U.S. Objectives in Indonesia," speech to the American Community at Bandung, Indonesia, 1960 February 23; 1 typewritten copy.
  - Unused speeches, 1 typewritten, 1 photocopy.
  - "Walk At Liberty," speech at the Daycroft School Commencement, Greenwich, Connecticut, 1971 May 29; 6 copies (3 photocopies, 3 reprints in booklet containing Commencement addresses), 4 Commencement Programs.
  - "Working Together in Achieving Liberty and Justice For All," speech to the Police Association, 1967 July 16; 2 carbon copies.
  - "World Review,", 1960 March 24; 1 typewritten copy.
  - "Youth and the World's Future," speech to the Troy Boy's Club, Troy, New York, 1970 January 13; 2 copies (typewritten, 1 photocopy).
- Subject File, 1939-1972 (Box 50-91)
  Reports, memoranda, printed material, lists, clippings, etc., arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
  - Adams, Sherman (Box 50)
  - Agricultural development
  - Alliance for Progress
  - American Foreign Service Association
  - American Indonesian Chamber of Commerce, Inc.
  - American Society for Engineering Education
  - Asia
    - General
    - Economic conditions
    - History
      - Newspaper clippings
  - Asian Almanac
  - Asian Survey
  - Association for Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN)
  - Atlantic Community News
  - Australia
  - Baguio, Philippines
  - Ball, George W.
  - Barnett, A. Doak
  - Barnett, Robert W.
  - Bavaria, Statistical Handbook, 1946
  - Berding, Andrew
  - Berlin
    - Economic conditions